+1 (519) 897-7857 | basiljoy001@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/basil-joy-b99089115/

A competent Software Engineer with nearly **8 plus years** of experience in IT Industry Development of IT Applications. Experience with **Banking, Telecommunication, Education and Travel** domain.

- Competent in Design and Development of Applications as per Clients Business needs and provide recommendations.
- Manage scrum team and support team members.
- · Handled the overall functioning of teams by implementing processes/Procedures in line with pre-set guidelines.
- Good role model and Mentor for the Team to achieve organization goals.
- Proven skills in managing work in sync with corporate set parameters & motivating peers for achieving business and individual goals.
- Strong collaboration, interpersonal skills with proficiency at grasping new concepts/technology quickly & applying the same in a productive manner.
- A good listener/ problem solver and deft in organizing, interpreting and communicating information to facilitate decision making process.
- Strong understanding of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) concepts.
- · Experience with Agile/Scrum methodologies.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

C# | Typescript | MVC | WEB API | Dot Net Core | Microservice | ASP.NET Web Forms | VB.NET | | EntityFramework | ADO.NET Angular | React | PRIME NG | Kendo UI | HTML/CSS/JavaScript | jQuery | Ajax | SQL SERVER | MONGO DB | Kafka | RabbitMQ | GIT | Azure CI/CD Pipeline | DevOps

#### INTERPERSONAL SKILLS:

Verbal Communication | Leadership, Ownership | Team Management | Task Delegation | Time Management | Critical Thinking | Active Listening | Open-Mindedness | Willingness to Learn

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Nest Digital Private Limited.**

## Senior Dot Net Full Stack Developer

September 2021 - May 2023

Key Project: NPSS (National Payment Systems Strategy) Banking Solution

This system delivers the core payment system capabilities of the UAEIPP system, including Real-time credit transfer and direct debits, which are cleared and settled on either a real time or a batch basis.

Technologies Used: Dot Net Core, Web API, c#, Kafka, Azure pipelines, HTML, JavaScript, Angular, XML, SQL Server.

- Web API creation and enhancement.
- Microservice creation from scratch.
- · Create NuGet and implement it in modules.
- Implemented Kafka configuration for consuming and producing messages.
- Kafka fine tuning to improve performance.
- Create tools for performance testing and support Performance testing.
- Development support for creating Azure pipelines.
- Central Bank message integration.
- Microservice creation from scratch.
- · Communication with integration team and resolve issues.

.

#### March 2020 - September 2021

# Senior Dot Net Full Stack Developer

Project: IB Aurora

Education software supporting schools, teachers from pre-school to higher education including examination boards, central governments, and other professional institutions. The system can mark papers and analysis the result.

Technologies Used: Dot Net Core, Web API, c#, Azure Service Bus, Azure pipelines, HTML, JavaScript, React, Chart JS, SQL Server.

- · User Story development.
- Team mentoring and coordination.
- Debugging and defect support.
- · Communication with Business analyst and solution architect.
- Implement third party library like Chart JS and introduce component in the application.
- Worked in UI design and client scripting with the help of HTML, CSS, jQuery.

#### OneViewIT Solutions.

### **Dot Net Full Stack Developer**

December 2018 - December 2019

Project: Booking Portal -Travel

It is a web application based on travel domain. It has facility for online flights and hotels bookings. The user can search flights and hotels, it will list all the results from multiple providers. From the list the user can select and book.

Technologies Used: MVC 4, SQL Server, Html, jQuery, Ajax, CSS, XML

- · Worked on Routing, Controllers and Filter for implementing new features in ASP.NET MVC applications.
- Travel providers API Integration.
- · UI enhancement changes and production support.

#### **DRD Communications and Software**

### **Full Stack Developer**

October 2016 - November 2018

**Project:** Unity Agent

It is a web application that enhances the BroadSoft user experience by making all features and services available. Unity agents simplifies the making and receiving calls and provides easy access to advanced functions. Users can also be able to do advanced call features like conference call.

Technologies Used: .NET MVC, C#, Html, Angular, SQL Server and procedures.

- Software development using .NET.
- · Integration with BroadSoft, Analysis documents and create XML requests.
- Implement all call control buttons functionalities.
- · Integrated Third party UI library Prime NG.

## **Tecrizon Labs**

# Junior .NET Developer

**June 2015 – September 2016** 

Project: Travel Mate – Rental Management

The project included the internal operations of the travel industry, like vehicle rental activities (RA opening, RA-closing, auto taxi rental) and reservations.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

- · Master of Computer Applications, Anna University Chennai, India
- · Bachelor of Computer Applications, MG University, India